<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autonomous Database on Mark’s Tech Notes</title>
    <link>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/tags/autonomous-database/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Autonomous Database on Mark’s Tech Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/tags/autonomous-database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tips to Speed Up Data Pump Imports into Autonomous Database (ADB)</title>
      <link>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/speeding-up-data-pump-imports-adb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/speeding-up-data-pump-imports-adb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many DBAs prefer using &lt;strong&gt;Oracle Data Pump&lt;/strong&gt; when migrating data into &lt;strong&gt;Autonomous Database (ADB)&lt;/strong&gt;, largely because the tool is familiar and reliable. However, Data Pump imports can become slow and resource-intensive, especially when migrating databases larger than &lt;strong&gt;100 GB&lt;/strong&gt;. In one customer case I was involved in, a &lt;strong&gt;650 GB import&lt;/strong&gt; into ADB took &lt;strong&gt;18 hours&lt;/strong&gt; to complete - clearly a pain point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few simple adjustments can dramatically reduce import times and make the overall migration process smoother.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Peer Database Role Switchover (ADW Serverless → ADW Dedicated) supported?</title>
      <link>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/adw-peer-switchover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/adw-peer-switchover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When planning a migration from Autonomous Data Warehouse (ADW) Serverless to ADW Dedicated, one question that often comes up is whether you can use a peer or standby database setup — similar to a traditional &lt;strong&gt;Data Guard switchover&lt;/strong&gt; — to transition environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s break down what that would involve and what Oracle actually supports.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-proposed-scenario&#34;&gt;The Proposed Scenario&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea typically goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set up a &lt;strong&gt;standby (peer) database&lt;/strong&gt; on Exadata Dedicated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Perform a &lt;strong&gt;role switchover&lt;/strong&gt;, making the Dedicated database the new primary.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Later, upgrade to &lt;strong&gt;23ai&lt;/strong&gt; as part of the post-migration plan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This approach essentially models a &lt;strong&gt;Data Guard–based migration&lt;/strong&gt;, using role switchovers to minimize downtime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
