<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autonomous Database on Mark’s Tech Notes</title>
    <link>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/categories/autonomous-database/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Autonomous Database on Mark’s Tech Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/categories/autonomous-database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Replication: ATP to ADW with OCI GoldenGate</title>
      <link>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/atp-to-adw-replication-with-goldengate-cloud-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/atp-to-adw-replication-with-goldengate-cloud-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/strong&gt; Senior DBAs, Cloud Architects, and Oracle User Groups&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Context:&lt;/strong&gt; Replicating SOE schema between 4-ECPU Autonomous instances&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-environment--performance-profile&#34;&gt;1. Environment &amp;amp; Performance Profile&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To provide a baseline for these benchmarks, both the source and target environments were configured as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; ATP (&lt;code&gt;dbai26&lt;/code&gt;) — &lt;strong&gt;4 ECPUs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target:&lt;/strong&gt; ADW (&lt;code&gt;PerfDB23ai&lt;/code&gt;) — &lt;strong&gt;4 ECPUs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; ~700 MB (SOE Schema)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-load-via-dbms_datapump&#34;&gt;Initial Load via &lt;code&gt;DBMS_DATAPUMP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used the &lt;code&gt;DBMS_DATAPUMP&lt;/code&gt; PL/SQL package to integrate directly with OCI Object Storage via &lt;code&gt;DBMS_CLOUD&lt;/code&gt; credentials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why use ZDM or DMS to migrate large databases from ADB-S to ADB-D without the drama</title>
      <link>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/why-use-zdm-to-migrate-large-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/why-use-zdm-to-migrate-large-databases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A customer I am working with is in the process of migrating a massive &lt;strong&gt;75TB database&lt;/strong&gt; from Autonomous Database Serverless (ADB-S) to Dedicated (ADB-D), which is a high-stakes operation where downtime isn&amp;rsquo;t an option. In addition, ADB-S has bi-weekly/monthly maintenance windows which can interfere with the migration process if it takes too long, that makes it critical to complete the migration in a timely manner.  While Oracle offers a suite of tools like Data Pump and GoldenGate, the sheer volume of data makes the &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; just as important as the &amp;ldquo;what.&amp;rdquo;. At this scale, the primary challenge isn&amp;rsquo;t just moving the bytes; it’s maintaining absolute data integrity while the source database continues to process thousands of transactions per second.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Database Middleman: Why You Shouldn&#39;t Bridge Cloud Storage via DBFS</title>
      <link>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/the-database-middleman---dbfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/the-database-middleman---dbfs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In modern Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI) architectures, architects often look for ways to manage file payloads without bloating the database. A common proposal is to use the &lt;strong&gt;Database File System (DBFS)&lt;/strong&gt; to attach an external &lt;strong&gt;File Storage Service (FSS)&lt;/strong&gt; to an &lt;strong&gt;Autonomous Transaction Processing (ATP)&lt;/strong&gt; database.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intent is usually good: keep the database lean while using its familiar interface to manage files. However, in practice, this creates a &amp;ldquo;Database Middleman&amp;rdquo; that introduces significant performance and operational risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying ATP Connectivity - Connect to ATP using Basic/EZConnect, TNS and/or JDBC</title>
      <link>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/atp_connection_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markstechnotes.github.io/MyBlog/posts/atp_connection_notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Autonomous Database (ATP), we are often told to simply &amp;lsquo;download the wallet and point the tool at the folder.&amp;rsquo; When it works, it feels like magic; when it fails, it feels like an impenetrable wall of networking protocols. Most developers spend hours troubleshooting &amp;lsquo;Connection Refused&amp;rsquo; errors when they try connecting using the &lt;code&gt;Wallet-less&lt;/code&gt; connection types: &lt;code&gt;Basic\EZConnect&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;TNS&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;JDBC&lt;/code&gt; because they view the connection string as a cryptic incantation rather than a logical map. This post is the result of a deep dive into the &amp;lsquo;why.&amp;rsquo; and will hopefully help you if you face similar connection issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
